《絕命律師》前請提要
Previously on "Better Call Saul."
你再犯一次就三振出局
This is both strike one and strike two.
霍華德不能因為我做的事
Howard can't just stick you in doc review
就把你弄來復審文件
because of something I did.
我告訴過你后果就是這樣
I told you this would happen.
我搞砸了
I screwed up!
這就是子彈的痕跡
That came from a bullet!
那你和凱莉要離開這棟房子
That's it, we're getting you and Kaylee out of this house.
錢包
Wallet!
放手
Let go!
你就這點能耐
That all you got?
我犯了什么不得了的大錯
What did I do that was so wrong?
你就像個酒鬼拒絕承認自己有毛病
You're like an alcoholic who refuses to admit he's got a problem.
來吧  查克
Come on down, chuck!
跟我一起在地上打滾吧
Roll around in the dirt with me!
-太美味了  -韭蔥的味道會不會太嗆
- Wonderful. - ‭Are the leeks too overpowering?
一點也不
Not at all.
和我們在佛羅倫薩吃的味道一樣棒
That's as good ‭as the one we had in Florence.
-別討好我  -我沒有
- All right, don't humor me. ‭- I'm not.
排練得如何
How was rehearsal?
那女的有好好表現嗎
Did what's-her-name behave herself?
她覺得整個章節都是她的似的
She takes the whole section for granted.
我還在糾結要不要跟她說
I'm debating ‭whether to say something.
我認為你該說出來  真的
I think you should, absolutely.
別憋在心里
Don't keep it inside.
準備放菜絲了嗎
Ready for the chiffonade?
好  謝謝
Yeah. Thanks.
畢竟  如果她影響了整個表演...
And after all, if she's compromising the work...
這很難說
Mm. Well, it's debatable.
舒伯特那部分還不錯
I mean, the Schubert is coming along nicely.
主要是士氣的問題
It's more about morale.
士氣會影響質量
Morale can affect quality.
天知道霍華德是如何赴湯蹈火
God knows the hoops that Howard jumps through
-才讓員工保持士氣的  -的確
- just to keep the troops humming. - ‭Well, true.
該給你的廚藝頒個獎
You deserve a medal for this.
沒什么大不了的
Please. It's no big deal.
這是你的醬油泡姜腌汁嗎
Your soy-ginger marinade?
我看到個檸檬的好像還挺好吃
Well, I found a citrus one that looked good,
所以我想試試
so I thought I would try that.
總之  你是個勤勞且毫無怨言的人
Well, anyway, you are a trouper.
我道歉在先
I apologize in advance.
他是...需要慢慢適應才會喜歡上的那種人
Let's just say he's... something of an acquired taste.
他能有多糟糕呢
Oh, how bad can he be?
以防萬一吧  我們先約個暗號
Well, just in case, let's have a high sign.
卡洛爾·伯納特招牌動作如何
How about ‭the old Carol Burnett thing?
美國女演員
她拉耳垂的動作嗎
Oh, where she pulls her earlobe?
沒錯
Exactly.
你做這個動作  我就會說我還要讀報告
You do this, and I'll say I have briefs to read,
-然后我們就能擺脫他  -好  就隨你意
- and we'll get rid of him. - All right. Whatever you want.
你知道她為什么拉耳朵嗎  卡洛爾·伯納特
You know why she did that -- Carol Burnett?
有趣的故事
It's a great story.
那是給她奶奶打的暗號
It was a signal to her grandmother,
她將她撫養長大...
who had raised her, as --
沒搞錯吧
Seriously?
他來早了
He's early.
你真可愛
You're a doll.
我的天  看看這地方
Holy shit. Look at this place.
吉米  歡迎
Hey, Jimmy, thanks for coming.
抱一個
Bring it on in here.
給你帶了點家鄉味
Hey! ‭Little taste of home for you.
找遍了城里的商店才買到的
Had to look all over town to find a place that had it.
來不及包裝
‭Didn't have time to wrap it.
謝謝
Well, thanks.
可以了
You're good.
好
Yeah.
我在找地方落腳
I'm looking for a place.
最近都住在華美達酒店
Been staying at the Ramada.
對了  感謝你幫忙
And thanks for the help, by the way.
我已經找到幾個中意的地點
I've found a few that I like.
有個帶泳池的地方
This one place, ‭the beachcomber, has a pool.
因為我們麥吉爾家的人
And since the Mcgill clan
皮膚簡直比白鼠還白
is whiter ‭than a pack of albino rats...
我覺得我該曬曬黑了
‭...I figure I better start working on my tan.
所以我真覺得那個地方不錯
So, seriously considering that option.
我強烈建議涂防曬油
I strongly suggest sunscreen.
我們這兒可是海拔一千五百米
We're up about 5,000 feet here.
你會曬傷的
You'll fry.
好主意  防曬油...  打勾
Excellent point. Sunscreen -- check.
你是...小提琴家
So... A violinist?
聽查克說  你非常有天賦
And according to Chuck, a crazy talented one at that.
真佩服
Mm. ‭I mean, wow.
查克過獎了
Well, Chuck is very gracious.
她又謙虛了
She's being modest.
麗貝卡在同行中備受尊敬
Rebecca is widely respected amongst her peers.
華裔大提琴家
馬友友還參加了我們的婚禮
‭Yo-yo Ma came to our wedding.
這真的...
That's, um...
棒極了
Right on, man.
說到你們婚禮
About the wedding, um,
我一直想道歉
I've been meaning ‭to apologize...about that.
-我真的很抱歉沒能  -不要緊的
- I am truly sorry I wasn't... - No worries, please.
說說在哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的第一周吧
So, tell us about your first week at Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
很棒啊
It was great.
我被安排在收發室工作
I mean, they got me working in the mailroom, which
萬事開頭難嘛
you gotta start somewhere.
我學會了用靜電復印機
I learned how to use the Xerox machine,
驚人得復雜
which is surprisingly complicated.
以前按下一個按鍵  彈出一張紙
I mean, press a button, a piece of paper spits out --
現在不一樣了
Not anymore. ‭Mm.
這機器簡直是臺電腦
Thing's practically a computer.
簡直像宇宙飛船一樣
It's like goddamn space shuttle.
它會雙面打印  自動裝訂
It's got, like, double-sided printing, automatic stapling, you know?
認識了許多男的女的  都很友好
Met some nice folks -- guys and gals.
其實就一個女的
Well, gal -- singular, actually.
記住了大家的名字  舔了無數張郵票
Learned everyone's name, and I licked a ton of stamps.
舌頭已經像漢堡肉一樣了  真的
My tongue is like hamburger meat -- I mean, seriously.
是吧
Yeah?
舌頭都舔破了
I got -- thing's raw as hell.
然后才發現有專用的海綿
Then I found out ‭there's a sponge for that.
哎呦  新手錯誤
Oops! Rookie mistake.
看來你第一周收獲挺多嘛
Well, it sounds like you had a very productive week.
是啊  真的很棒
Yeah, it was really great.
我想對你們說
Hey, guys, um...
謝謝你們邀請我做客
Um, I want to thank you for having me over.
這是我十年來吃的最美味的一餐
This is, like, the best meal I've had in a decade.
魚做得很完美  而且這個
I mean, the fish is perfection, and the, uh...
意大利燴飯
Risotto.
謝謝夸獎
Thank you. That's very kind.
你真是個好廚師
Well, you're a wonderful chef, you know?
不僅是小提琴天賦秉異
Aside from being super talented with the...
你娶了位賢妻  查克  真走運
You got a good one, Chuck -- I mean, lucky, lucky man.
干杯
‭Well, ‭cheers to that.
不好意思
Pardon me.
好了
All right.
吸塵器和摩托車上的律師
What's the difference between a vacuum cleaner
有何不同
and a lawyer on a motorcycle?
吸塵器的塵袋[混蛋]在里面
The vacuum cleaner ‭has the dirt bag on the inside.
律師是坐在外面的混蛋
啊哈  律師笑話
Aha, lawyer jokes.
我才在收發室待了一個星期
I've only been in the mailroom a week,
可能就聽了上百個了
and I've heard maybe a hundred.
這都是出于對律師的敬愛
Yeah. ‭It all comes ‭from a place of affection.
當然
Sure. Of course.
把《教父》和律師弄到一起會得到什么
What do you get when you cross the Godfather with a lawyer?
《教父》中有臺詞"an offer you can't refuse"
此處指律師說的專業術語讓人費解
一個你聽不懂的提議
An offer you can't understand.
好機靈的笑話
Very clever.
這個沒聽過
Never heard that one.
相信我
And believe me --
我對你的職業抱有最大的尊敬
I have nothing but the utmost respect for your profession.
這是支柱...
I mean, ‭it's the pillar of -- oh!
為什么要把律師埋在六米深的土下
Why do they bury lawyers under 20 feet of dirt?
因為在內心"深處"  他們其實是好人
Because deep down, ‭they're really good people.
一個智商六十的律師應該叫什么
Uh, w-what do you call a lawyer with an IQ of 60?
"法官大人"
"Your honor."
律師和虱子的區別在哪
What's the difference between a tick and a lawyer?
不
Oh, no.
你死了  虱子就會離開你的身體
The tick falls off when you're dead! Bam!
律師在你死后還會纏著你
好喜歡這個
Love that one.
你喜歡這個嗎  我只是開玩笑
You like that? Just joking.
你要知道  我對我的職業是認真的
I want you to know ‭how seriously I take my job.
我真的很感謝  對了
I'm, uh, grateful for the -- oh.
換一個電燈泡要幾個律師
How many lawyers does it take to change a light bulb?
這個很經典
Classic setup here.
三個  一個爬梯子  一個搖晃梯子
Three -- one to climb the ladder, one to shake it,
還有一個起訴生產梯子的廠家
And one ‭to sue the ladder company.
很經典
Comedy gold.
-我能說一整晚  -接著說
- I'm here all night! - More. Go, go.
好的  好好好
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
有人要甜點嗎
Dessert, anyone?
我們有自己做的藍莓酥餅配香草冰激凌
We have a homemade blueberry crumble with vanilla ice cream.
藍莓酥餅  好呀  聽起來好棒
Yeah, blueberry crumble -- sounds terrific.
我喜歡有水果的  藍莓的
I love a fruit-based, uh, blueberry --
-等等  我也想起來一個  -快說
- Wait. I think I know one. - Oh, bring it on.
好啊
Yeah, yeah.
律師和精子的共同點是什么
Um, what do lawyers and sperm have in common?
這個
Oh, just... ‭Um.
三百萬  不不
3 million -- no, wait.
三百萬分之一
Um, 1 in 3 million...
-有機會成為人類  -有機會成為人類
- have a chance ‭of becoming a human being. - Of becoming a human being.
這個我喜歡
Love that one.
晚餐進行得不錯  你覺得呢
Well, that went well, don't you think?
當然  還是要謝謝你
Sure. Thanks again.
我不知道你在擔心什么
I don't know ‭what you were worried about.
吉米挺好的
Jimmy's great.
是挺好的  不   他有點
Yeah. No, he's...
沒什么
Yeah.
明天要做什么
So, what's going on tomorrow?
十點要幫戈恩斯泰特作證詞
Well, I've got the ‭Gernstetter deposition at 10:00,
午飯后要連開幾場合伙人會議
Back-to-back partner meetings after lunch.
應該不會太晚
It shouldn't be a late one.
那女的事情你想得怎么樣了
Thought any more about what's-her-name?
那也關系到你的名聲  不是嗎
It's your reputation, too, you know?
我們周一先從柴可夫斯基開始
Well, we start the Tchaikovsky on monday,
我看看結束時她的狀態怎么樣
so I'll see what kind of mood she's in when we wrap.
聰明
Smart.
二十五個律師被水泥埋到下巴了  你該說什么
What do you call 25 attorneys buried up to their chins in cement?
-水泥還不夠  -什么
- Not enough cement. - ‭What?
絕命律師
第二季 第五集
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
翻譯  喃喃  TheWalkingNerd  喵球球  克里斯
翻譯  自然卷  咦個芝麻糕  楊愛菜
詹姆斯·麥吉爾
翻譯  杏仁斯嘉麗  西陵折枝     校對  喃喃
時間軸   喃喃  夢龍  姜姜
你好  這是金·韋克斯勒的語音信箱
Hello. You've reached the voicemail of Kim Wexler.
請留言
Please leave me a message,
后期 四月追番的小新  總監  喃喃
我會盡快回復你
and I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
又是我
It's me again.
我想到了一個方法能幫你擺脫那里
Look, I think I found something that could help get you outta there.
打開微信   掃描左側二維碼
或搜索公眾號:    美劇炸了
了解最新影視資訊字幕信息
我會彌補這一切的
I'm gonna make things right.
給我回個電話吧
Call me, would you?
你好
Hi.
抱歉  我沒打算嚇你一跳
Sorry. I didn't mean to sneak up on you.
-我以為大家都走了  -沒有
- I just thought everyone was gone. ‭- Nope.
我一般都待到很晚
I'm here late most nights.
順便提一句  我在你辦公室看到...
By the way, ‭i noticed in your office...
你扔掉了一個易拉罐
You threw away a soda can.
你翻了我的垃圾
You're going through my trash?
沒有
No.
我只是午休時進去送文件
I was just dropping off papers at lunchtime,
無意中看到它在你的垃圾筒里
and I happened to notice it in your trash can.
我把它拿出來了  沒事了
I fished it out, so it's fine.
辦公室的垃圾筒是扔可回收紙張的
Office cans ‭are for recyclable paper --
廚房里有個單獨的大垃圾桶用來放塑料
there's a separate big can in the kitchen for plastic,
玻璃和鋁金屬
glass, and aluminum.
我們這里十分重視生態足跡
We take our ecological footprint pretty seriously here.
好吧  也就是說
okay, so, the big can
大垃圾桶是扔我的威士忌酒瓶的地方
is where I should throw my empty Scotch bottles.
我明白的
No, I-I get it.
綠色生活
Go green.
好了  還有別的事嗎
Good. Was there anything else?
是的  還有一件小事
Yeah, one quick thing.
我這里有你早上給克利福德的簡報
I have the brief you gave Cliff this morning --
原告對被告動議的反對
the plaintiff's opposition to the defendant's motion?
我做了幾個批注
I have a few notes.
應該挺清楚了
I think they're pretty clear,
但如果我們能一起看一遍可能更輕松點
but it's probably easier if we just go over them together.
天啊  那是克利福德的批注
Jesus. Th-those are Cliff's?
不  是我的批注
No, they're my notes.
如果你有時間的話  咱們現在就過一遍吧
I'd love go to over them now, if you have a minute.
其實沒看上去這么糟
It looks worse than it is.
只是...我們有特有的版式
It's -- it's just that we have a particular house style.
無意冒犯
Okay, no offense,
不過  你是剛來兩年的員工吧
But, uh, you're a second-year associate, right?
-是的  -我有四年了
- Yep. ‭- And I came in as a fourth-year.
沒錯
That's right.
那為什么一個兩年員工要給四年員工做批注
So, why is a second-year giving notes to a fourth-year?
就像我說的  我清楚版式要求
Well, like I said, I know the house style.
是克利福德派你來當我保姆的嗎
Does Cliff have you babysitting me?
不是
No.
這只是同事之間互相幫助
This is just one associate helping another.
比如這里  羅馬數字標題
Like here, ‭the Roman numeral headings --
全都要大寫
we use all caps for those.
你用的是縮進  這當然沒問題
And you indented them, which is perfectly fine,
不過克利福德更喜歡居中
but Cliff likes them centered.
差點忘了
Oh, and before I forget,
所有文件中  在句號后面都要空兩格
we put two spaces after a period on all our documents.
這的確不是什么大事
I know it seems like a minor thing,
但這樣頁面會整潔得多
but really looks so much cleaner on the page.
你所做的引述有點多
You went a tad overboard with the quotations.
引用主導性法律意見是沒問題的
It's okay to present a quote from a controlling legal opinion,
但如果你引用過多
but when you use too many,
它會打亂你論述的節奏
it disrupts ‭the flow of your argument,
而且讓人感覺
and it gives the impression
你沒法獨立寫作論述
you don't know how to write an argument of your own.
你當然知道怎么寫
‭And I'm sure you do, so...
你有過度使用"顯然"  "無疑"之類詞的傾向
‭You have a tendency to overuse the words "Clearly" and "Obviously."
這又是個人見解的問題...
Again, it's a matter of personal opinion --
我真的很感激  艾琳
I really appreciate this, Erin,
但是  我正打算出去
But, uh, ‭I was just on my way out.
我們能不能明天一早再繼續討論
So, if we could continue this first thing tomorrow morning...
我覺得我們應該現在就看完
Well, I was thinking we should just get 'er done now.
分秒必爭啊
No time like the present.
當然
Sure.
讓我們卷起袖子  大干一場吧
Let's roll up our sleeves and apply a little elbow grease.
太好了
Great!
我去拿我最喜歡的筆
So, I'm gonna get my favorite pen,
然后馬上去找你
and I will see you momentarily.
沒問題
You got it.
韋克斯勒小姐
Uh, Miss Wexler?
你可以叫我金
You can call me Kim.
金  已經十一點四十了
Kim, it's 20 to midnight.
你在問能不能走嗎
Are you asking me if you can leave?
伙計們  我又不是你們上司
Guys, I'm not your supervisor.
不用因為我留下來
Don't stick around on my account.
一起走嗎  金
You coming, Kim?
隨后就走
Right behind you.
只要完成最后這一份
Just finishing up this last one.
斯韋卡特和考科利
又打擾你了  謝了
Again, thanks.
杰蘇阿爾多  你今晚可以不清潔嗎
Hey, Gesualdo, could you skip vacuuming tonight, please?
就五分鐘  就給我五分鐘
Five minutes -- just give me five minutes.
這就是解決這場鬧劇的方法
Here's how we're gonna handle this travesty of justice.
韋克斯勒訴哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
Wexler vs. Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill --
你想要我起訴我的公司嗎
You want me to sue my own firm?
文件都打印好了  蓄勢待發
Filing's all typed up. It's ready to go.
這不是我的專長
This is not my area of expertise, all right?
所以首先要做的
So, first order of business --
我們要找一個專門處理勞工法的律師
we get a great employment-law attorney.
讓他們知道我們是認真的
Show 'em we mean business.
說真的
‭Come on.
你看看你
Hey, look at you. ‭
你半夜還在這看似榮耀實則監獄的地方
Okay, you're here at midnight in this glorified cellblock
努力工作  是為了什么
busting your ass -- for what?
跟你的表現一點關系也沒有
It has nothing to do with your performance.
你受到了不公對待
You're being mistreated.
查克是通過懲罰你來牽制我
Chuck is punishing you to get to me.
這是敲詐  簡單明了
This is extortion, pure and simple.
不  是霍華德要維護形象
No, that's Howard, ‭who has an image to uphold.
凱特爾曼案慘敗后他也這么做的
He did the same thing after the Kettleman fiasco,
查克也沒有干預
and Chuck was nowhere in sight.
我告訴你  查克就是罪魁禍首
I'm telling you -- Chuck is behind this.
不  你才是罪魁禍首
No, you are behind this.
我告訴過你后果  現在我就在付出代價
I told you this would happen, and now I'm paying the price.
我要是早知道就好了
I shoulda known better.
現在我要保持低調  熬過去
So now I'm keeping my head down, and I'm getting through this.
而且我肯定不會起訴哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
And I'm most certainly not suing HHM.
-金  -就算我勝訴了  誰還會雇傭我
- Kim - Even if I won, who would hire me?
那是自斷前程的行為
That would be career suicide.
好吧
All right.
那我退出戴維斯梅因律所
Then I quit Davis & Main.
那有什么用
What does that accomplish?
這是唯一可以讓你脫離困境的方法
It's the only way to get you outta dutch
因為這和查克有關
because this is about Chuck,
不管你信不信
whether you want to believe it or not.
我給他想要的  他就會寬恕你
I give him what he wants -- he lets up on you.
我的白馬王子
My knight in shining armor.
真是不小的犧牲啊
That is some sacrifice --
辭掉你一開始就在毀掉的工作
Quitng a job that you've been trying to tank since day one.
不是這樣的
That's not true.
我自己想辦法脫離困境
I dig myself out of this hole.
你做你的工作  吉米
You do your job, Jimmy.
向我證明你可以做到一周  不  一天
Prove you can go one week -- hell, one day --
不違反新墨西哥律師協會的規則
without breaking the rules of the New Mexico Bar Association
或者不惹你老板生氣
or pissing off your boss.
還有不要侮辱我的智商
And don't insult my intelligence
說這么做都是為了我
by saying you are doing any of this for me.
你救不了我
You don't save me.
我才能救自己
I save me.
請你走吧
Just please go.
世上第二棒的律師
艾琳在嗎
Hey, is Erin in yet?
該死的煩人鬼
God damn pixie ninja.
實在對不起
I owe you a big apology.
我生了一個病...
I have a medical condition --
胃食管反流病
Gerd, ‭gastroesophageal reflux disease.
我知道  很繞口對不對
I know -- it's a mouthful, right?
它會影響下食道括約肌
It affects ‭the lower esophageal sphincter.
我昨天午餐時冒險吃了些洋蔥圈
I took a risk yesterday at lunch with some onion rings,
然后昨晚...
and last night --
我們還要不要工作
Are we doing this or not?
當然
You bet.
杰瑞  我是金·韋克斯勒
Hey, Jerry. It's Kim Wexler.
校友會怎么樣了
How's things with the alumni group?
前五十
Top 50?
新墨西哥大學法學院好樣的
Go, UNM law!
你有沒有聽說過圣達菲
Hey, wondering if you've heard that Santa Fe place
在尋找新的外聘律師
is looking for new outside counsel.
他們真的應該考慮
They should really be considering
哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所  我們...
Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill. We --
一定是謠言
Must've just been a rumor.
好啊  改天喝一杯
Yeah, let's grab a drink soon.
你也是  好的  再見
You too. Okay, bye.
我記得你提過
Hey, uh, I remember you mentioned
你哥哥曾在英特爾法律部門工作
your brother worked in Intel's legal department.
我是哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的律師
I'm an attorney at Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
你知不知道
Would you happen to know
英特爾是否對他們的法律代表滿意
if Intel is happy with their legal representation?
我受寵若驚
That's -- that's flattering,
但我已經有男朋友了  所以...
but I'm seeing someone at the moment, so...
這樣吧
you know what?
打我電話  他們會找到我的
Just call the main number, and they'll find me.
好  不  我們幾天前喝過了
Yeah, no, we had drinks a few days ago.
她說你有個朋友...
And she said you had a friend who...
所以他們已經解決了
Oh, so they already settled.
我聽說你是哈佛法學院的
I heard you ended up at harvard law.
對  沒錯  她是我室友
Yeah, yeah, she was my roommate.
我是哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的律師
Listen, uh, I'an attorney at Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
我們因與其他律所合作處理大合同而聞名
We're actually known for teaming with other firms on large contracts.
斯韋卡特嗎
Schweikart?
當然  我很了解他們  很棒的律所
Sure. Yeah, I know them well. It's a great firm.
我們在去年美國律師協會聯誼會上見過
We met at that ABA mixer last year.
沒錯  波旁酒  就是我
Yep, bourbon shots. That was me.
恭喜你拿下了霍尼韋爾的合同
well, congrats on landing that Honeywell contract --
可不輕松呢
Huge amount of work.
你也是
You, too.
-中午吃得好嗎  -不錯
- How was your lunch? - ‭Good.
-你吃什么了  -火雞卷
What'd you have? ‭Uh, turkey wrap.
那地方怎么樣
How's the place?
很棒
It's great.
安全又安靜
It's safe, quiet.
允許狗進入
They allow dogs.
我很滿意了
I can't ask for more than that.
凱莉就是不肯出游泳池
I can't get Kaylee out of the pool.
一天結束準曬成小黑炭
By the end of the day, she's a prune.
她喜歡那兒我真高興
‭I'm glad she's enjoying it.
我得馬上給她準備晚飯了
Hey, I better get her dinner started soon.
下館子吧
Go to the restaurant.
不  太貴了  屋里有吃的
No, it's too expensive. I have groceries in the room.
不用擔心那個
Oh, don't worry about that.
-帶她出去  -謝謝  麥克
- Take her out. ‭- Thanks, Mike.
她想你
She misses you.
你一會兒能過來嗎
Do you think you might come by later?
還不行
Oh, not yet.
我不想讓她看見我這個樣子
I don't want her to see me lookin like this.
情況有多糟
How bad was it?
我跟你說  我的下一輛車一定要有氣囊
Well, I can tell ya the next car I get's gonna have airbags.
你想什么時候來都行
Well, ‭whenever you feel you're ready.
沒關系  看起來比較糟糕而已
Ah, it's okay. ‭It looks worse than it is.
替我親凱莉一口
You give Kaylee a kiss for me.
我會的
I will.
好的  再見  親愛的
All right. Bye, darlin.
等等
Hold up.
你怎么了
What the hell happened to you?
我懂  搏擊俱樂部的第一條規則是吧
I get it -- the first rule of fight club, right?
給你介紹一下
Uh, let me introduce you.
這是我的保姆  艾琳
This is my babysitter, Erin.
艾琳  這是我的爺爺  麥克
Erin, this is my grandpa, Mike.
很高興見到你
Nice to meet you.
謝了  蒂姆
Thanks, Tim.
很高興見到你  吉米
Good seein you, Jimmy.
這個職員跟我是老相識了
Listen, this clerk and I go way back.
我倆很鐵
We're like this.
但需要施點巧計  所以讓我來可以嗎
But she needs a little finessing, so can I handle it?
可以啊
Yeah, sure.
驚喜啊
Surprise!
你肯定以為再也見不到我了吧
Bet you never thought you'd see me again.
我需要和布雷訴奧康納一案的米夏埃利斯
I need a summary judgment hearing
進行簡易審判的聽證
with Michaelis for Bray v. O'Connell,
希望是周四十點  在他...之前
And I'm hopin for Thursday at 10:00, before he, uh...
沒空
Don't have it.
周四十二點呢
Thursday at noon, perhaps?
沒有
Nope.
周四下午兩點  這是最后...
Thursday at 2:00 -- now, that's my final --
你真漂亮
You're pretty.
你可以做我的新媽媽嗎
Will you be my new mommy?
你在做什么
What are you doing?!
-搞什么  -這是賄賂
- What? ‭- That's a bribe.
這是禮物
It's a gift.
在這里就是這么辦事的
That's how it works here --
司法之輪需要"潤滑"
grease the wheels of justice.
-給我  -不能這樣
- Give me -- - That's not how it works.
提交文件  確定日期  就這樣
You submit the paperwork, and you get a date -- period.
你懂不懂什么叫略施巧計啊
What don't you understand about finessing?
我為我的同事道歉
I apologize for my colleague.
她是新來的
She's new.
有沒有其他辦法定個周四的時間呢
Is there any possible way we could still get Thursday?
給你周四下午兩點半
I'll give you 2:30 Thursday.
十四號
The 14th.
那是下個月了
That's next month.
好吧就那天
We'll take it.
這會寫入我的斯塔西報告嗎
So, does this go ‭on my official stasi report?
原東德秘密警察
我這不是給你惹麻煩
I'm not trying to get you in trouble --
而是避免讓你惹上麻煩
I'm trying to keep you out of it.
我要上男廁所
I'm gonna hit the men's room.
男廁所
The men's room.
比爾  最近怎么樣啊
Hey, how you doing, Bill?
我怎么樣  你還好嗎
How am I doing? How are you?
勉強過活唄
Oh, you know, hanging in.
聽說你去戴維斯梅因律所了
Yeah, word on the street is you're over at Davis & Main now.
你個幸運的混蛋
You lucky son of a bitch.
你知道的  和惡魔共舞
Ah, you know, dancing with the devil.
地檢官那里的事情如何...
So, how are things ‭at the district attorney's--
戴維斯梅因
Davis & main!
那鐵定很爽吧
Man, that must be sweet!
給你配車了嗎
Give you a car?
肯定給你配了車
Bet they gave you a car.
是啊  他們給我配了車
Yeah. They gave me a car.
-什么車  -是一部...
- What kind? - ‭It's a --
停  別告訴我  我不想知道了
No, don't tell me. I don't want to know.
肯定是德國車  是德國車嗎
I bet it's German. Is it German?
是德國車
Yeah, it's German.
杯架其實有點...
Uh, the cup holder's actually --
你辦公室也很豪華吧
You have a sick office?
肯定特別豪華
I bet you have a sick office.
是很豪華
Pretty sick.
里頭還有一個小壁爐
It's got a little fireplace.
壁爐
Fireplace?
為了壁爐我能把我媽殺了
I'd kill my mother for a fireplace.
給我個窗戶我也能把她殺了
Hell, I'd kill her for a window.
你還有助理是吧
You, uh, you have an assistant, right?
別告訴我...她很辣吧
Don't tell me -- is she hot?
她很辣是吧
She's hot, right?
我的助理是個叫奧馬爾的小伙子
She is a bright young man named omar.
奧馬爾
Omar.
你衣服上沾了些...
Hey, you got a little something on your, uh...
嘔吐物...又來了
That's vomit...Again.
最糟糕的是...
The worst part --
可能來自兩個不同的被告
Could've come ‭from two different defendants.
人渣  都是人渣
Scumbags. They're all scumbags.
對了  你住哪兒  給你安排住處了嗎
Oh, my god. Where you living? They put you up?
我住在公司臨租房  就...
It's a corporate apartment. It's just --
停  住嘴
Ah, no, don't tell me.
天吶
Christ.
糟了  我得走了
Ah, damn it. I gotta run.
我要去處理幾個白癡...
I'm putting away ‭some brain-dead suck wad...
他們試圖搶劫圖書館
who tried to rob a library.
很高興見到你  比爾
Good seeing you, Bill.
祝你愉快
Have a great day.
走狗屎運的混賬
Lucky bastard.
喂  你好
Hello. Hi.
我是金·韋克斯勒
It's Kim Wexler.
我給您留了言  我只是...
I did leave a message, and I was just...
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
抱歉打擾到您了
Sorry to bother you.
你好  我是金·韋克斯勒
Hi. This is Kim Wexler.
我想找卡羅琳·利佩茲
I was looking for Carolyn Lipitz.
不是秘書  我是一名律師
No, not his secretary. I'm an attorney.
是的  克里斯把你的電話給了我
Yes, I did -- I got your number from Chris.
當然  我會給他們說的
Sure. I will let them know.
好的  不  明白了
Okay. Nope, got it.
完全明白
Totally understand.
我是哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的金·韋克斯勒
This is Kim Wexler from Hamlin Hamlin & Mcgill.
其實...我能...
Actually -- hey -- can I just --
你能告訴他我之后再打給他嗎
Would you tell him I'll call him right back?
好的  請告訴我什么時候合適
Okay. Just let me know when is a good time.
明白
Got it.
好  辛苦您了
Okay. Thanks for your time.
喂  克勞迪婭
Hi, Claudia.
我是金·韋克斯勒
It's Kim Wexler.
我會跟他說的
I'll let him know.
我是金·韋克斯勒
This is Kim Wexler.
我想找吉利安·高根
I was looking for a Jillian Kogan.
去年我在美國律師協會聯誼會上認識你的
I met you last year at an ABA mixer.
你知道我恐高
You know I have a fear of heights.
每年夏天都來
Keep coming every summer.
好  有消息的話請跟我說一聲
All right, just give me a call. Great.
我是金·韋克斯勒  我昨天打過電話了
Kim wexler. I did call yesterday.
好  我明白了
Okay. I totally get it.
金·韋克斯勒  你還好嗎  佩奇
Kim wexler. Hey. How are you, Paige?
是嗎
You did?
那...那真是個好消息啊
That's -- that's so nice to hear.
我覺得我們也很合拍呢
I thought we hit it off, as well.
真的嗎
Really?
我...
I --
我真的特別激動
I, uh, I-I couldn't be more thrilled.
我是說  律所和我都很激動
It -- I mean, the firm and I.
當然  我現在就跟他說
Absolutely. I'll tell him right now.
明天肯定就能辦好...
I'm sure we can get something on the books tomorrow --
最遲后天
Day after, at the latest.
謝謝你  佩奇
Thank you, Paige.
我也是  好  再見
Me, too. Okay, bye.
太好了
Yes!
-她在這兒呢  -你好
- There she is. ‭- Hi.
-你好  -佩奇  很高興見到你
- Hi. - ‭Paige, so good to see you.
我也是
You, too.
金  這是凱文·沃弛泰爾  公司總裁
Kim, this is Kevin Wachtell, our C.E.O.
我是金·韋克斯勒  很高興認識你  凱文
Kim Wexler. ‭Great to meet you, Kevin.
我也是
And you.
兩位  這是霍華德·哈姆林  高級合伙人
Uh, Paige, Kevin, this is Howard Hamlin, our senior partner.
-很高興認識你們  -我們也是
- Pleasure. - ‭Likewise.
很高興你們能來到這里
We're thrilled ‭to have you folks here.
凱文  跟你說個真實的故事  我七歲時
Kevin, true story -- when I was 7 years old,
我的第一個銀行賬戶就在梅薩維德銀行
my very first bank account was at Mesa Verde,
你能相信嗎
if you ‭can believe it.
我信  我也是  那時我爸還負責經營呢
I can. Mine was, too, back when my dad ran the place.
我記得我第一本存折的封面
I can remember ‭the cover of my first passbook.
-是剪影...  -牛仔的剪影
- It was a silhouette of a... - Cowboy.
馬背上的牛仔  站在仙人掌旁邊
Cowboy on horseback, yes, standing next to a cactus.
我喜歡那牛仔
I loved that cowboy.
我那時一直在為買下那匹馬攢錢
Far as I was concerned, I was saving up for that horse.
不然錢對于一個七歲小孩來說又有什么用呢
What the heck else is money good for when you're 7 years old?
我們在會議室中為你準備了
So, we have ‭a little presentation for you
一次小小的展示  還準備了零食
in our conference room, along with some snacks
和寫著你名字的豆奶拿鐵
and a soymilk latte with your name on it.
她可真能干
This one -- she's a keeper.
請吧
Shall we?
走吧
Let's do it.
我認為這樣再好不過了
Well, I think that ‭couldn't have gone any better.
-很高興見到你  -棒極了  再見
- Pleasure to meet you. - ‭Fantastic. I'll see you soon.
感謝你安排這一切  再見
Thanks for setting this up. Talk to you soon.
很高興見到你  佩奇
Lovely to meet you, Paige.
恭喜
Congratulations.
同喜
Right back at you.
我之后會和佩奇談談  讓一切順利進行
I'll circle back with Paige, get the ball rolling,
開始談戰略
start talking strategy, you know?
或者列個清單  看看派哪些律師去處理
Maybe...put together a list of staff associates we can put on this.
讓法蘭西斯做吧
I'll put Francis on that.
復審文件已經夠你忙的了
You've got enough on your plate in doc review.
來了
Coming.
我來得不是時候嗎
Catch you at a bad time?
當然不  進來吧
Not at all. Come in.
我聽見叮當聲了
I hear clinking.
我們要慶祝什么嗎
Does that mean ‭we have something to celebrate?
當然了
We sure do.
我們要慶祝什么
What are we drinking to?
給你弄了個肥差
Got a juicy one for you.
-梅薩維德銀行  -預付聘金
- Mesa Verde? - ‭On retainer.
那更好了
Oh, even better.
恭喜
Congratulations.
是你在高爾夫球場上爭取到的嗎
One of your golf-course conquests?
金·韋克斯勒帶來的
Kim Wexler brought them in.
一個四年律師爭取到了二十五萬的活兒
Fourth-year associate snags a quarter of a million in billings?
她自己可能也在喝酒慶祝呢
She's probably having a couple of drinks herself.
我猜  她應該再次受到重用吧
She's out of the doghouse, I assume?
再說吧
We'll see.
跨州擴張  這案子很復雜
Interstate expansion -- it's a complex case.
我們可能要對付兩個  甚至三個監管委員會
That's two, maybe three regulatory commissions we'll be dealing with
律所可能得忙上幾個月  甚至幾年
Months of work for HHM, maybe years.
早上好  魯道夫
Good morning, Rudolpho.
早上好  麥吉爾先生
Good morning, Mr. McGill.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我不知道這兒有人
I didn't know anyone was here.
我來送些磯鷂渡的材料
Just dropping off some Sandpiper stuff.
你來早了
You're in early.
其實是待晚了
More like late.
不管現在幾點  見到你真高興
Well, regardless of the hour, good to see you here.
我在做些新嘗試
Yeah, ‭I'm trying something new.
我來這一直工作到早九點
I'm coming in, working until 9:00.
律所開門之前辦公更容易
It's easier before the place opens,
燈還沒亮  電話也不會響個不停
without all the lights and the phones ringing.
想喝點咖啡嗎
How about some coffee?
不用了  謝謝
No, thank you.
那你能幫我泡點咖啡嗎
W-would you mind making me some?
對不起
I apologize.
我沒法自己做
It's just I-I can't do it myself,
我不能碰電器
what with the electricity.
-好  -不加糖
- Sure. ‭- No sugar.
稍微加點豆奶
Just a splash of soy milk.
應該有
I think we have it.
金
Kim?
泡兩杯
Um, make two cups.
他們應該說得對
Well, I guess it's true what they say --
早起的鳥兒有蟲吃  如果你喜歡蟲子的話
The early bird gets the worm, which is good if you like worms.
我能問個問題嗎
May I ask you a question?
當然
Of course.
我在這家律所有前途嗎
Do I have a future at this firm?
你我有很多共同點
We have a lot in common, you and I.
我弟弟讓你獨自承擔責任
My brother left you holding the bag.
要知道
If it makes you feel any better,
你不是第一個為他擔風險的人
you're not the first person to go out on a limb for him.
我總是反復犯同樣的錯誤
I made the same mistake over and over again.
結果現在霍華德也犯了
And now Howard has...
他怨你
And he blames you.
真是一團亂
It's a damned mess.
吉米跟你說過我們的爸爸的事嗎
Jimmy ever tell you anything about our father?
沒怎么說過
Not much, no.
我爸爸  我們的爸爸  他是
My dad -- our dad -- he was --
典型的好人
well... the personification of good.
我都不知道他能不能看見任何罪惡
I'm not sure he could even see sin in any form,
他似乎就沒這個基因
like he was born without the gene.
他在西塞羅市經營一家街角小店
He ran a little corner store in Cicero --
賣賣煙草  散裝糖果
cigarettes behind the counter, penny candy --
沒什么特別的  但是能維持家用
nothing special, ‭but it kept food on the table.
鄰居們都很喜歡他
And the neighborhood loved dad.
他叫得出每個人的名字  了解他們的生活
He knew everybody's name, what was going on in their lives.
他讓這個小小的拐角變得更好
This little corner -- he made it better.
我是以他的名字命名的
I was named after him.
在那之前  他在很多人手下工作過
Before that, he'd worked for a lot of people over the years,
他的夢想就是自己當老板
and his dream was to be his own boss --
傾其所有開了這個小店
put everything he had into that place.
他讓吉米在店里干活兒的時候我在外面上大學
I was away at college when he put Jimmy to work there.
吉米從小就在店里  看著爸爸長大
Jimmy grew up in that store, watching our father.
但我爸不善經營
But dad was not the world's greatest businessman,
最終資金周轉不靈
and eventually, ‭he ran into money troubles.
那時候我在當法庭書記員
I, um, ‭had a clerkship at the time,
但我還是回家去幫他理清賬目
but I came home to help him get his books in order,
解決問題
set the ship straight.
我不是會計
Now, I'm no accountant,
可我發現少了一萬四千塊
but I discovered $14,000 was just gone.
就在這些年里無緣無故消失了
Vanished over the years.
結果是吉米陸陸續續偷的
Turns out Jimmy had pilfered it in dribs and drabs --
直接從收銀臺拿的
just took it out of the till.
我爸聽不進去
My dad wouldn't hear it.
不可能  不是他的吉米干的
Nope. Not his Jimmy.
最后他只能賣了那小店
He ended up having to sell.
半年后  他去世了
Six months later, he was dead.
葬禮上  吉米哭得撕心裂肺
At the funeral, ‭no one cried harder than Jimmy.
我弟弟不是壞人
My brother is not a bad person.
他本性善良
He has a good heart.
只是
It's just...
他控制不住自己
...he can't help himself.
所以只能大家幫他收拾爛攤子
And everyone's left picking up the pieces.
還有咖啡嗎
Is there any coffee left?
不  我來吧
No, I got it.
我會跟霍華德談談
I'll talk to Howard,
幫你們調解調解
pour a little oil on troubled waters.
讓你在下面復審文件太大材小用了
You're being wasted down in doc review.
梅薩維德銀行的業務拉得好
Good job with Mesa Verde.
請進  正在營業  今天沒活  回家睡覺
我能坐這嗎
Mind if I join you?
你好
Hi.
需要點什么嗎
What can I get you?
咖啡  清咖
Coffee -- black.
馬上就來
Coming right up.
他是把你揍得挺慘的
He really did a number on you.
抱歉  我認識你嗎
Sorry. I know you?
打你的那個年輕人
The young man who did that to you.
他是我侄子  一直都這么莽撞
He's my nephew -- ‭hothead, always has been.
以為自己是個拳擊手
Kid thinks he's a boxer.
他應該尊重你
He should have shown you respect.
我代表我們全家向你道歉
I apologize to you on behalf of my family.
接受道歉
Apology accepted.
你知道嗎
And you know what?
他是該進監獄  這對他再好不過
He should go to jail -- best thing for him.
讓他學會尊重長輩
Teach him respect for his elders.
但是  用不著待八年
But... not for eight years --
應該少好幾年
less, much less.
你懂我的意思嗎
You see what I'm getting at?
不怎么懂
Not really.
非法持有槍支  得判八年  可能十年
The gun charge -- that's 8 years he's going away, maybe 10.
重度攻擊  非法持槍  還搶了你的錢包
Aggravated assault, the gun, plus he got your wallet.
沒錯
That's right.
我希望你能告訴警方
I would like for you to tell the police
槍是你的
that the gun was yours.
是嗎
Would you?
他懷疑你撞了他的車
You're both ‭a little hot under the collar
你們倆都沒控制住情緒
about whether ‭you bumped his car or not.
你們扭打了起來  然后他搶了你的槍
But there was a scuffle, and, uh, he got your gun.
我的槍
My gun?
他從你的口袋里拿了你的槍
Your gun from your pocket -- he got it,
所以槍上有他的指紋
and that's how his prints got on it.
那我就要面臨非法持槍的指控了
And then I'd be subject to the gun charge.
你當過警察
You're an ex-cop.
他們不會為難你
They'll go easy on you.
原來你還知道別人怎么想
So you're a psychic.
我會擰著屠庫的耳朵讓他給你道歉
I'll even twist Tuco's ear, make him apologize.
他的罪名只有毆打他人  沒有其他的了
And he serves for battery -- nothing else.
這結果對大家都是最好的
I'm looking for the best possible outcome for everybody.
至于你的麻煩
And for your trouble...
給你五千塊
you take home $5,000.
好好考慮一下
Think about it.
各大應用市場均可下載
人人美劇APP新版本上線啦
在線看劇全面修復
給你更佳追劇體驗
掃碼即刻下載